<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ruby | Adventures in Programming]]></title>
  <link href="http://statonjr.github.com/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://statonjr.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-18T19:54:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://statonjr.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Larry Staton Jr.]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[12-factor-app]]></title>
    <link href="http://statonjr.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/12-factor-app/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T11:41:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://statonjr.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/12-factor-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Richard Schneeman from Heroku will be presenting the <a href="http://www.12factor.net">12 Factor App</a> at the charlotte.rb meeting next Wednesday night at Packard Place. I read through the website and I'm interested to see how the 12 Factor App compares to how I've architected some of my systems. I've already found a few changes that I should make. I'm also interested to see how the 12 Factor App differs from an environment like <a href="http://www.torquebox.com">Torquebox</a>, which handles many of these factors for you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[hello world]]></title>
    <link href="http://statonjr.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T19:49:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://statonjr.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I write code. I leared to write code at age 10; I wrote BASIC on an Apple IIe. I then moved on to AppleScript, a language that I still use today to boss Mac apps around. At my current job, I write mostly Ruby code, building APIs and other tools for teams inside a large financial institution. While I currently deploy on MRI, I am a big fan of JRuby and I plan to port most of my APIs over to JRuby, so expect several posts on deploying JRuby.</p>

<p>I also write Cocoa and iOS applications for fun and profit. While I write my iOS applications in Objective-C, I write my Cocoa apps with MacRuby. With MacRuby, I get full access to AppKit and Foundation from Ruby, even on the command line, not to mention the ability to create great interfaces in Xcode.</p>

<p>Other languages that I'm interested in include LISP, Clojure, JavaScript, Factor, and R. I admit that it's an eclectic mix, but I trained to be a lawyer, so I never had to learn about functional languages or stack languages. I'm still baffled my LISP macros, but I vow to conquer them.</p>

<p>My goal for this blog is to contribute what I've learned back to the community. Many people contributed to my success and I hope to return the favor.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
